"It opened up something in me that needed to be opened and needed to heal," says Elizabeth Russell, a teacher and librarian from the US state of Connecticut.
"它打开了我内心需要被打开和治愈的东西，"美国康涅狄格州的教师兼图书管理员伊丽莎白·拉塞尔说。
She was going through a rough patch in life when she found bibliotherapy.
当她正在经历人生低谷的时候，她发现了阅读疗法。
Bibliotherapy is the use of literature to support people with mental health and wellbeing issues.
阅读疗法是利用文学来鼓励有心理健康和幸福感问题的人。
The benefits of non-fiction, self-help books are well documented – results from 'A meta‐analysis of bibliotherapy studies' suggest this type of bibliotherapy can help with conditions such as anxiety and depression – but what about fiction?
非虚构类自助书籍的好处已有充分记录——"阅读疗法研究的荟萃分析"的结果表明，这种类型的阅读疗法可以帮助治疗焦虑和抑郁等状况——但虚构类作品呢？
'Creative bibliotherapy' may have similar advantages.
"创造性阅读疗法"可能具有类似的优势。
Ella Berthoud, well-known bibliotherapist and author of The Novel Cure calls it 'the art of prescribing fiction for life's ailments'.
著名的阅读治疗师、《小说疗法》一书的作者埃拉·伯索德称之为"为生活病痛开具小说处方的艺术"。
But how does it work?
但它是如何起作用的呢？
If you were to go to Ella for help, she'd start with a consultation.
如果你去找埃拉寻求帮助，她会从咨询开始。
Then, she says, "I will guide you to books that put a finger on feelings you may often have had, but perhaps never clearly understood before."
然后，她说："我会引导你去读一些书，它们能帮你准确指出你可能经常有、但以前也许从未清楚理解的那些感受。"
Proponents of creative bibliotherapy say that immersing oneself in a good book can help readers process emotions, discover coping strategies or even just provide some escapism from life's stresses.
创造性阅读疗法的支持者表示，沉浸在一本好书中可以帮助读者处理情绪，发现应对策略，或者甚至只是提供一些逃避生活压力的方式。
But some experts worry the benefits of creative bibliotherapy are overhyped.
但一些专家担心创造性阅读疗法的好处被夸大了。
Studies suggest reading may improve things such as empathy and self-confidence, but in terms of treating specific mental health conditions, the evidence is weak.
研究表明阅读可以改善同理心和自信心等，但在治疗特定心理健康状况方面，证据不足。
Some stories may even cause harm, particularly if they trigger or reinforce the negative feelings someone wants to escape.
有些故事甚至可能造成伤害，特别是如果它们触发或强化了某人想要逃避的负面情绪。
It seems bibliotherapy is best used in conjunction with other therapies, rather than as a substitute.
看来阅读疗法最好与其他疗法结合使用，而不是作为替代品。
In the UK, the Reading Agency's Reading Well programme helps people manage their health and wellbeing with books.
在英国，阅读机构的"阅读好"项目帮助人们通过书籍管理自己的健康和福祉。
The books are recommended by health experts and people with lived experience of the topics covered.
这些书籍由健康专家和有相关主题亲身经历的人推荐。
But, the organisation's head of health and wellbeing, Gemma Jolly, understands that it's "not a one size fits all."
但是，该机构健康与福祉负责人杰玛·乔利明白，这"并非一种万能的解决方案"。
She says, "It's about having an additional tool that might work for some people."
她说："这是一个额外的工具，可能对某些人有帮助。"
Will you give bibliotherapy a go?
你会尝试一下阅读疗法吗？